
Programming Paradigm


Paradigm : A typical example or pattern of something;

Syntax doesnt matter.
Programming Paradigms matter.


Modular Programming
Structured Programming is also known as Modular Programming and a subset of procedural programming language.

Programmers work with abstractions every day. An abstraction highlights the essential features of something while ignoring its details. An abstraction could encompass a piece of hardware, a software component, and so on. 

The two most important elements of a module are the division of the module into an interface and an implementation and the ability to hide information in the implementation. 